const e="We could not find what you asked for, but got you this",o="chemistry",t=200,i=120,a=[{id:2,question:"What mass of water is produced when 8.0g of hydriogen reacts with excess oxygen [H = 1, O = 16]",option:{a:"36.0g",b:"8.0g",c:"72.0g",d:"16.0g"},section:"",image:"",answer:"c",solution:"",examtype:"utme",examyear:"2001"},{id:27,question:"As the concentration of an electrolyte reduces, the conductivity",option:{a:"Reduces to zero",b:"Decreases",c:"Increases",d:"Is unaffected"},section:"",image:"",answer:"b",solution:"",examtype:"utme",examyear:"2001"},{id:113,question:"Carbohydrates are compounds containing carbon, hydrogen and oxygen in the ratio",option:{a:"3:01:01",b:"2:01:01",c:"1:02:01",d:"1:01:01"},section:"",image:"",answer:"c",solution:"",examtype:"utme",examyear:"2003"},{id:209,question:"Phenolphthalein in acidic solution is",option:{a:"Colourless",b:"Yellow",c:"Red",d:"Orange"},section:"",image:"",answer:"a",solution:"",examtype:"utme",examyear:"2005"},{id:175,question:"N2(g)  +  3H2(g)  ⇌   2NH2(g)   Δ H = - 90kJ  In the equation above, the yield of ammonia can be decreased by",option:{a:"Adding a catalyst",b:"Removing ammonia",c:"Increasing the pressure",d:"Increasing the temperature"},section:"",image:"",answer:"d",solution:"",examtype:"utme",examyear:"2005"},{id:16,question:"Phosphorous is stored under water to precvent it from",option:{a:"Dehydrating",b:"Becoming inert",c:"Smelling",d:"Catching fire"},section:"",image:"",answer:"d",solution:"",examtype:"utme",examyear:"2001"},{id:83,question:` I.  H = 1s1
II. O = 1s22s22p4
III. N = 1s22s22p3
IV. Zn = 1s22s22p63s23p64s23d10
From the above, which of the following pairs is likely to be paramagnetic?
`,option:{a:"I and II",b:"I and  III",c:"I    and IV",d:"III  and IV"},section:"",image:"",answer:"a",solution:"",examtype:"utme",examyear:"2003"},{id:294,question:"The residual solids from the fractional distillation of petroleum are used as",option:{a:"Raw materials for the cracking process",b:"Fuel for driving tractors",c:"Fuel for jet engines",d:"Coatings for pipes"},section:"",image:"",answer:"d",solution:"",examtype:"utme",examyear:"2010"},{id:226,question:"What is the mola. Mass of a substance, if 0.4 mole of the substance has a mass of 25.0g",option:{a:"6.3g",b:"40.0g",c:"62.5g",d:"2.5g"},section:"",image:"",answer:"c",solution:"",examtype:"utme",examyear:"2006"},{id:54,question:"The furring of kettles is caused by the presence in water of",option:{a:"Calcium trioxocarbonate(IV)",b:"Calcium tetraoxosulphate(VI)",c:"CALCIUM HYDROXIDE",d:"Calcium hydrofentrioxocarbonate(IV)"},section:"",image:"",answer:"d",solution:"",examtype:"utme",examyear:"2002"},{id:168,question:"In the production of soap, concentrated sodium chloride solution is added to",option:{a:"Increase the solubility of the soap",b:"Decrease the solubility of the soap",c:"Saponify the soap",d:"Emulsify the soap"},section:"",image:"",answer:"b",solution:"",examtype:"utme",examyear:"2004"},{id:109,question:"The metal that liberates hydrogen from cold water in bubbles only is",option:{a:"Na",b:"K",c:"Ca",d:"Al"},section:"",image:"",answer:"c",solution:"",examtype:"utme",examyear:"2003"},{id:303,question:" Two hydrocarbons X and Y were treated with bromine water. Decolorized the solution and Y did not. Which class of compound does Y belong",option:{a:"Alkynes",b:"Alkenes",c:"Alkanes",d:"Benzene"},section:"",image:"",answer:"c",solution:"",examtype:"utme",examyear:"2010"},{id:203,question:"The solubility curve shows the variation of solute concentration with",option:{a:"Volume",b:"Vapour density",c:"Pressure",d:"Temperature"},section:"",image:"",answer:"d",solution:"",examtype:"utme",examyear:"2005"},{id:69,question:"Hydrogen is readily released when dilute hydrochloric acid reacts with",option:{a:"Au",b:"Cu",c:"Na",d:"Ag"},section:"",image:"",answer:"c",solution:"",examtype:"utme",examyear:"2002"},{id:301,question:"One of the major uses of Alkanes is",option:{a:"In the hydrogenation of oils",b:"In the textile industries",c:"In the production of plastics",d:"As domestic and industrial fuels"},section:"",image:"",answer:"d",solution:"",examtype:"utme",examyear:"2010"},{id:131,question:"The shape of the s-orbital is",option:{a:"Spherical",b:"Elliptical",c:"Spiral",d:"Circular"},section:"",image:"",answer:"a",solution:"",examtype:"utme",examyear:"2004"},{id:279,question:"Which of the following salts is slightly soluble in water",option:{a:"CaSO4",b:"Na2CO3",c:"PbCl2",d:"AgCl"},section:"",image:"",answer:"a",solution:"",examtype:"utme",examyear:"2010"},{id:160,question:"Oxyacetylene flame is used for iron-welding because it",option:{a:" makes the iron metal solidity very quickly",b:"Combines with oxygen to give a pop sound",c:"Evolves a lot of heat when burnt",d:"Dissociates to produce carbon (IV) oxide and oxygen"},section:"",image:"",answer:"c",solution:"",examtype:"utme",examyear:"2004"},{id:73,question:"The gas that gives brown colouration in brown ring test",option:{a:"Co2",b:"NO2",c:"NO",d:"CO"},section:"",image:"",answer:"b",solution:"",examtype:"utme",examyear:"2002"},{id:117,question:"The type of reaction that is peculiar to benzene is",option:{a:"Addition",b:"Hydrolysis",c:"Polymerization",d:"Substitution"},section:"",image:"",answer:"d",solution:"",examtype:"utme",examyear:"2003"},{id:183,question:"What is the valence shell electron configuration of the element with atomic number 17",option:{a:"1s22s22p63s23p5",b:"1s22s22p63s23p4",c:"3s23p5",d:"2s22p6"},section:"",image:"",answer:"a",solution:"",examtype:"utme",examyear:"2005"},{id:98,question:"If Y is an oxidizing agent that reacts with a reducing agent, Z, which of the following is correct",option:{a:"Y increases in oxidation number",b:"Y becomes reduced",c:"Z loses protons",d:"Z gains protons"},section:"",image:"",answer:"b",solution:"",examtype:"utme",examyear:"2003"},{id:243,question:"When a crystal was added to the clear solution of its salt, the crystal did not dissolve and the solution remained unchanged. This showed that the solution was",option:{a:"Supersaturated",b:"Unsaturated",c:"Saturated",d:"Concentrated"},section:"",image:"",answer:"c",solution:"",examtype:"utme",examyear:"2006"},{id:237,question:"Which of the following has an isomer",option:{a:"C4H10",b:"C6H6",c:"C2H4",d:"C2H6"},section:"",image:"",answer:"a",solution:"",examtype:"utme",examyear:"2006"},{id:280,question:"6AgNO3(aq)  +  PH3(g) +    3H2O(l)      →    6Ag(s)+   H3PO3(aq)   +    6HNO3(aq)  In the reaction above, the reducing agent is",option:{a:"H2O(l)",b:"PH3(g)",c:"AgNO3(aq)",d:"HNO3(AQ)"},section:"",image:"",answer:"b",solution:"",examtype:"utme",examyear:"2010"},{id:221,question:"Forms a layer of oxide on the metal   If the heat of combustion of hydrogen is -285.8kJ. what is the heat of formation of water",option:{a:"-285.8Kj",b:"-571.6kJ",c:"+571kJ",d:"+285.8kJ"},section:"",image:"",answer:"a",solution:"",examtype:"utme",examyear:"2006"},{id:260,question:"Which of he following pairs of substances will react further with oxygen to form a higher oxide",option:{a:"SO2 and NO",b:"CO2 and H2O",c:"CO and CO2",d:"NO and H2O"},section:"",image:"",answer:"a",solution:"",examtype:"utme",examyear:"2006"},{id:67,question:"Ordinary glass is manufactured from silica, Ca CO3 and",option:{a:"K2CO3",b:"NaHCO3",c:"Na2CO3",d:"K2SO4"},section:"",image:"",answer:"c",solution:"",examtype:"utme",examyear:"2002"},{id:100,question:"In the electrolysis of a concentrated solution of sodium chloride using inert electrodes, which of the following ions are discharged at the cathode and anode respectively",option:{a:"Na+ and Cl-",b:"Na+ and OH-",c:"H+ and OH-",d:"H+ and Cl-"},section:"",image:"",answer:"d",solution:"",examtype:"utme",examyear:"2003"},{id:198,question:"Which of the following are structural isomers",option:{a:"Propanoic acid and propan-1, 2-diol",b:"Ethanoic acid and propanoic acid",c:"Ethan-1, 2 –diol and ethanoic acid",d:"Propanal and propanone"},section:"",image:"",answer:"d",solution:"",examtype:"utme",examyear:"2005"},{id:143,question:"ZnO(s) + CO (g) → Zn(s) + CO2 (g). ",option:{a:"Decomposed",b:"Displaced",c:"Oxidized",d:"Reduced"},section:"",image:"",answer:"d",solution:"",examtype:"utme",examyear:"2004"},{id:218,question:"The ion that can be used as an oxidizing agent is",option:{a:"Fe3+",b:"F-",c:"Ca2+",d:"Au3+"},section:"",image:"",answer:"c",solution:"",examtype:"utme",examyear:"2006"},{id:93,question:"When 10g of sodium hydroxide is dissolved in 1000cm3 of water, the solution formed is approximately   [Na = 23, H = 1, O = 16]",option:{a:"0.01 mol dm-3",b:"0.10 mol dm-3",c:"0.25 mol dm-3",d:"0.50 mol dm-3"},section:"",image:"",answer:"c",solution:"",examtype:"utme",examyear:"2003"},{id:80,question:"Neutral atoms of neon with atomic number 10 have the same number of electrons as",option:{a:"O2+",b:"Ca2+",c:"K+",d:"Mg2+"},section:"",image:"",answer:"d",solution:"",examtype:"utme",examyear:"2003"},{id:239,question:"One mole of a hydrocarbon contains 36g of carbon and its vapour density is 20. The structure of the hydrocarbon is",option:{a:"CH3CH2CH3",b:"CH3CH = CH2",c:"CH3CH2C = CH",d:"CH3C = CH"},section:"",image:"",answer:"d",solution:"",examtype:"utme",examyear:"2006"},{id:29,question:"NH3(g)  +  HCI(g)  → NH4CI(s) The entropy change in the system is",option:{a:"Negative",b:"Indeterminate",c:"Positive",d:"Zero"},section:"",image:"",answer:"b",solution:"",examtype:"utme",examyear:"2001"},{id:253,question:"The sulphide which is insoluble in dilute hydrochloric acid is",option:{a:"CuS",b:"Na2S",c:"FeS",d:"ZnS"},section:"",image:"",answer:"a",solution:"",examtype:"utme",examyear:"2006"},{id:219,question:"Zinc and carbon rods are used as anode and cathode respectively in a",option:{a:"Voltaic cell",b:"Lead accumulator",c:"Leclanche cell",d:"Daniel cell"},section:"",image:"",answer:"c",solution:"",examtype:"utme",examyear:"2006"},{id:152,question:"Which of the following gases can be collected by the method of downward delivery",option:{a:"Chlorine",b:"Oxygen",c:"Ammonia",d:"Hydrogen"},section:"",image:"",answer:"a",solution:"",examtype:"utme",examyear:"2004"},{id:153,question:"Which steam is passed over red-hot carbon, the substances produced are",option:{a:"Hydrogen and trioxocarbonate(IV) acid",b:"Hydrogen, oxygen and carbon(IV) oxide",c:"Hydrogen and carbon (II) oxide",d:"Hydrogen and carbon (IV) oxide"},section:"",image:"",answer:"c",solution:"",examtype:"utme",examyear:"2004"},{id:190,question:"Which of these properties gives a solid its definite shape",option:{a:"Weak intermolecular attraction",b:"High boiling point",c:"High melting point",d:"Strong intermolecular attraction"},section:"",image:"",answer:"d",solution:"",examtype:"utme",examyear:"2005"},{id:185,question:"The density of a certain gas is 1.98g dm-3 at s.t.p. What is the molecular mass of the gas   [Molar volume of a gas at s.t.p = 22.4dm-3]",option:{a:"26.0g",b:"31.0g",c:"54.0g",d:"44.0g"},section:"",image:"",answer:"d",solution:"",examtype:"utme",examyear:"2005"},{id:165,question:"Vulcanization involves the removal of",option:{a:"A monomer",b:"The single bond",c:"The double bond",d:"A polymer"},section:"",image:"",answer:"c",solution:"",examtype:"utme",examyear:"2004"},{id:245,question:"When 5.0cm3 of a saturated solution of sugar of molar mass 342g at 400C was evaporated to dryness, 34.2g of dry solid was obtained. The solubility of sugar at 400C is",option:{a:"7.0 mol dm-3",b:"3.5 mol dm-3",c:"2.0 mol dm-3",d:"10.0mol dm-3"},section:"",image:"",answer:"c",solution:"",examtype:"utme",examyear:"2006"},{id:296,question:"Which of the following organic compounds is very soluble in water",option:{a:"C2H2",b:"C2H4",c:"CH3COOC2H5",d:"CH3COOH"},section:"",image:"",answer:"d",solution:"",examtype:"utme",examyear:"2010"},{id:147,question:` 2CO(g)  +  O2(g) →  2CO2(g)
Given that   Δ H [CO] is 110.4kJ mol-1 and Δ H [CO2] is -393.0kJ mol-1, the energy change for the reaction above is
`,option:{a:"-503.7kJ",b:"-282.6kJ",c:"+282.6kJ",d:"+503.7kJ"},section:"",image:"",answer:"N",solution:"",examtype:"utme",examyear:"2004"},{id:116,question:"The formula for ethyl butanoate is",option:{a:"C3H7COOC2H5",b:"C2H5COOC3H7",c:"C4H9COOC2H5",d:"C2H5COOC4H9"},section:"",image:"",answer:"a",solution:"",examtype:"utme",examyear:"2003"},{id:148,question:"Which of the following hydrogen halides has the highest entropy value",option:{a:"HF",b:"HCl",c:"HBr",d:"Hl"},section:"",image:"",answer:"a",solution:"",examtype:"utme",examyear:"2004"},{id:56,question:"When a salt loses its water of crystallization to the atmosphere on exposure, the process is said to be",option:{a:"Deliquescence",b:"Effervescence",c:"Efflorescence",d:"Fluorescence"},section:"",image:"",answer:"c",solution:"",examtype:"utme",examyear:"2002"},{id:22,question:"Ethanoic acid is",option:{a:"Tribasic",b:"Unionizeable",c:"Monobasic",d:"Dibasic"},section:"",image:"",answer:"c",solution:"",examtype:"utme",examyear:"2001"},{id:75,question:"What volume of oxygen is produced from the decomposition of 2 moles of KClO3 at s.t.p   [Molar volume of a gas at s.t.p = 22.4 dm3]",option:{a:"22.4 dm3",b:"33.6 dm3",c:"44.8 dm3",d:"67.2 dm3"},section:"",image:"",answer:"d",solution:"",examtype:"utme",examyear:"2003"},{id:240,question:"CH3-CH2-C = CH  The hybridization in the compound above is",option:{a:"Sp3 and sp",b:"Sp3 and sp2",c:"Sp",d:"Sp2"},section:"",image:"",answer:"a",solution:"",examtype:"utme",examyear:"2006"},{id:151,question:"The allotrope of carbon used in the decolourization of sugar is",option:{a:"Graphite",b:"Soot",c:"Charcoal",d:"Lampblack"},section:"",image:"",answer:"c",solution:"",examtype:"utme",examyear:"2004"},{id:174,question:"To obtain pure carbon(II) oxide from its mixture with carbon (IV)oxide, the mixture should be",option:{a:"Bubbled through concentrated Tetraoxosulphate(VI) acid",b:"Bubbled through sodium hydroxide",c:"Passed over heated copper(II) oxide",d:"Bubbled through water"},section:"",image:"",answer:"b",solution:"",examtype:"utme",examyear:"2005"},{id:225,question:"The solution that will conduct the highest amount of electricity is",option:{a:"2.0 moldm-3 of ethanoic acid",b:"0.5 mol dm-3 of ethanoic acid",c:"2.0 mol dm-3 of hydrochloric acid",d:"0.5 moldm-3 of hydrochloric acid"},section:"",image:"",answer:"c",solution:"",examtype:"utme",examyear:"2006"},{id:250,question:"Dynamic equilibrium describes a situation where",option:{a:"A reaction gives back the reactants",b:"Reactants are converted to products",c:"The concentration of reactants and products is equal",d:"Both forward and reverse reaction proceed at the same rate"},section:"",image:"",answer:"d",solution:"",examtype:"utme",examyear:"2006"},{id:88,question:"Which of the following ions is acidic",option:{a:"K+",b:"NO-3",c:"S2-",d:"H3O+"},section:"",image:"",answer:"d",solution:"",examtype:"utme",examyear:"2003"},{id:94,question:"A charge in the temperature of a saturated solution disturbs the equilibrium between the",option:{a:"Dissolved solute and the solvent",b:"Solvent and the undissolved solute",c:"Dissolved solute and the undissolved solute",d:"Dissolved solute and the solution"},section:"",image:"",answer:"c",solution:"",examtype:"utme",examyear:"2003"},{id:256,question:"Which of the following typically represents a photochemical reaction",option:{a:"Conversion of dinitrogen (IV) oxide to nitrogen(IV) oxide",b:"Conversion of silver halides to grey metallic silver",c:"Decomposition of calcium hydroxide to its oxide",d:"Formation of water from hydrogen and oxygen molecules"},section:"",image:"",answer:"b",solution:"",examtype:"utme",examyear:"2006"},{id:48,question:"A little quantity of Trichloromethane (b.pt.600C) was added to a large quantity of ethanol (b.pt.780C). the most probable boiling point of the resultant mixture is from",option:{a:"699C – 700C",b:"820C – 840C",c:"600C – 780C",d:"700C – 744C"},section:"",image:"",answer:"d",solution:"",examtype:"utme",examyear:"2002"},{id:146,question:"The mass of silver deposited when a current of 10A is passed through a solution of silver salt for 4830s is    [Ag = 108, F = 96500 Cmol-1]",option:{a:"108.0g",b:"54.0g",c:"27.0g",d:"13.5g"},section:"",image:"",answer:"b",solution:"",examtype:"utme",examyear:"2004"},{id:41,question:"The gas that can best be collected by downward displacement of air is",option:{a:"Chlorine",b:"Sulphur(IV)oxide",c:"Ammonia",d:"Carbon(IV)oxide"},section:"",image:"",answer:"c",solution:"",examtype:"utme",examyear:"2001"},{id:24,question:" 2SO2(g) + O2(g) ⇌  2SO3(g)  The equilibrium constant for the reaction above is increased by  [ΔH = -189kJ mol -1]",option:{a:"Increasing the temperature of the system",b:"Increasing the pressure of the system",c:"The addition of a catalyst to the system",d:"Increasing the surface area of the vessel"},section:"",image:"",answer:"b",solution:"",examtype:"utme",examyear:"2001"},{id:17,question:"In which of the following reactuions does reduction take place",option:{a:"Fe2+ - e-   Fe3+",b:"2O2-  → O2 + 4e-",c:"Cr - 2e-  → Cr2+",d:"2H+  +  2e-   →H2"},section:"",image:"",answer:"d",solution:"",examtype:"utme",examyear:"2001"},{id:20,question:"Which of the following best explains the increase in the rate of a chemical reaction as the temperature rises",option:{a:"The bonds in the reacting molecules are more readily broken",b:"The molecules collisions become more violent",c:"A lower proportion of the molecules has the necessary minimum energy to react",d:"The collision frequency of the molecules increases"},section:"",image:"",answer:"d",solution:"",examtype:"utme",examyear:"2001"},{id:201,question:"Kerosene is commonly used to remove the red colour stain of palm oil from clothes because it",option:{a:"Helps to spread the oil over a larger surface area",b:"Makes the oil evaporate easily by dissolving it",c:"Helps to dilute the oil and reduce its colour",d:"Reacts with the oil to form an odourless compound"},section:"",image:"",answer:"b",solution:"",examtype:"utme",examyear:"2005"},{id:33,question:"During the vulcanization of rubber, sulphur is added to",option:{a:"Break down rubber polymer",b:"Lengthen the chain of rubber",c:"Bind rubber molecules together",d:"Act as a catalyst"},section:"",image:"",answer:"c",solution:"",examtype:"utme",examyear:"2001"},{id:251,question:"The raw material used for the smelting of iron ore in a furnace is",option:{a:"Zn(NO3)2",b:"CaSO4",c:"CuSO4",d:"CaCO3"},section:"",image:"",answer:"d",solution:"",examtype:"utme",examyear:"2006"},{id:19,question:"A metal M displaces zinc from zinc chloride solution. This shows that",option:{a:"M is more electronegative than zinc",b:"Zinc is above hydrogen in the series",c:"M is more electropositive than zinc",d:"Electrons flow from zinc to M"},section:"",image:"",answer:"c",solution:"",examtype:"utme",examyear:"2001"},{id:34,question:"Catalytic hydrogenation of benzene produces",option:{a:"Oil",b:"Cyclohexane",c:"Cycloexane",d:"Margarine"},section:"",image:"",answer:"c",solution:"",examtype:"utme",examyear:"2001"},{id:60,question:"which of the following chlorides would exhibit the least ionic character",option:{a:"AlCl3",b:"CaCl2",c:"MgCi2",d:"LiCl"},section:"",image:"",answer:"a",solution:"",examtype:"utme",examyear:"2002"},{id:28,question:"In which of the following reactions has the oxidation number of nitrogen increased",option:{a:"2NO(g)  +  Br2(l)  → 2NOBr(l)",b:"2NO2(g)  +  O2(g)   → 2NO2(g)",c:"FeSO4(aq)  +  NO(g) → Fe(NO)SO4(s)",d:"2NO(g)  +  CI2(g) →  2NOCI(l)"},section:"",image:"",answer:"b",solution:"",examtype:"utme",examyear:"2001"},{id:178,question:"The most suitable metal that can be used as a lightening  conductor is",option:{a:"Aluminium",b:"Iron",c:"Copper",d:"Silver"},section:"",image:"",answer:"d",solution:"",examtype:"utme",examyear:"2005"},{id:125,question:"If a solution contains 4.8g of Tetraoxosulphate (VI) acid. Calculate the amount of copper(II) oxide that will react with it  [CU = 64, O = 16, S = 32, H = 1]",option:{a:"0.8g",b:"4.0g",c:"40.0g",d:"80.0g"},section:"",image:"",answer:"b",solution:"",examtype:"utme",examyear:"2004"},{id:292,question:"A compound gives an orange red colour to a non luminous flame. This compound is likely to contain",option:{a:"Ca2+",b:"Fe3+",c:"Fe2+",d:"Na+"},section:"",image:"",answer:"a",solution:"",examtype:"utme",examyear:"2010"},{id:63,question:"Which of the following statements is true of a proton.",option:{a:"The total mass of the protons in a particular nucleus always half the nuclear mass",b:"The mass of a proton is 1840 times the mass of an electron",c:"The mass proton is 1.0008g",d:"The mass of a proton is one-twelfth the molar mass of carbon"},section:"",image:"",answer:"b",solution:"",examtype:"utme",examyear:"2002"},{id:43,question:"Which of the followinig respresents hybridization in ethyne?",option:{a:"Sp2",b:"Sp2d",c:"Sp3",d:"sp"},section:"",image:"",answer:"d",solution:"",examtype:"utme",examyear:"2001"},{id:1,question:"25cm3 of a gas X contains Zmolecules at 150C and 75mmHg. How many molecules will 25cmm3 of another gas Y contain at the same temperature and pressure",option:{a:"2Y",b:"2Z",c:"Z",d:"Y"},section:"",image:"",answer:"c",solution:"",examtype:"utme",examyear:"2001"},{id:150,question:"Which of the following shows little or no net reaction when the volume of the system is decreased",option:{a:" H2(g)  +  l2(g)  ⇌  2Hl(g)",b:"2NO2(g)  ⇌  N2O4(g)",c:" PCl5(g)   ⇌ PCl3(g)  + Cl2(g)",d:" 203(g)   ⇌  3O2(g)"},section:"",image:"",answer:"a",solution:"",examtype:"utme",examyear:"2004"},{id:167,question:` Alkanol + Alkanoic acid ⇌  Ester + water.
The reverse reaction of the equation above is known as
`,option:{a:"Hydrolysis",b:"Saponification",c:"Hydration",d:"Fermentation"},section:"",image:"",answer:"a",solution:"",examtype:"utme",examyear:"2004"},{id:96,question:"The commonest feature of the reactions at the anode is that",option:{a:"Electrons are consumed",b:"Oxidation is involved",c:"Ions are reduced",d:"Electrode dissolves"},section:"",image:"",answer:"b",solution:"",examtype:"utme",examyear:"2003"},{id:214,question:"2H2 + O2  → 2H2O  ΔH = -571Kj  In equation above, how much heat will be liberated if 12.0g of hydrogen is burnt in excess oxygen?",option:{a:"-1713kJ",b:"+1142kJ",c:"-571kJ",d:"-1142kJ"},section:"",image:"",answer:"a",solution:"",examtype:"utme",examyear:"2005"},{id:195,question:"The decolourization of the purple colour of a tetraoxomanganate (VII) ion is a test for",option:{a:"Alkanals",b:"Alkanes",c:"Alkenes",d:"Alkanols"},section:"",image:"",answer:"c",solution:"",examtype:"utme",examyear:"2005"},{id:304,question:"The compound that is used as an anaesthetic is",option:{a:"CHCI3",b:"CH2C2",c:"CH3CI",d:"CCI4"},section:"",image:"",answer:"a",solution:"",examtype:"utme",examyear:"2010"},{id:26,question:"When ΔH is negative, a reaction is said to be",option:{a:"Ionic",b:"Reversible",c:"Exothermic",d:"Endothermic"},section:"",image:"",answer:"c",solution:"",examtype:"utme",examyear:"2001"},{id:197,question:"A substance that is used as a ripening agent for fruits is",option:{a:"Propene",b:"Methane",c:"Ethene",d:"Butane"},section:"",image:"",answer:"c",solution:"",examtype:"utme",examyear:"2005"},{id:9,question:"Which of the following statements is correct about the average kinetic energy of the molecules of a gas",option:{a:"It inctreasaes with increase in pressure",b:"It increases at constant pressure",c:"It increases with increase in temperature",d:"It increases in volume"},section:"",image:"",answer:"c",solution:"",examtype:"utme",examyear:"2001"},{id:163,question:"A characteristic of the alkane family is",option:{a:"Addition reaction",b:"Elimination reaction",c:"Substitution reaction",d:"Neutralization reaction"},section:"",image:"",answer:"c",solution:"",examtype:"utme",examyear:"2004"},{id:154,question:" sulphur (IV) oxide bleaches by",option:{a:"Reduction",b:"Oxidation",c:"Hydration",d:"Absorption"},section:"",image:"",answer:"a",solution:"",examtype:"utme",examyear:"2004"},{id:206,question:"The gas that is the most dangerous pollutant to humans is",option:{a:"Carbon(IV) oxide",b:"Nitrogen (II)oxide",c:"Hydrogen sulphide",d:"Sulphur(IV) oxide"},section:"",image:"",answer:"c",solution:"",examtype:"utme",examyear:"2005"},{id:145,question:"In the electrolysis of brine, the anode is",option:{a:"Platinum",b:"Copper",c:"Zinc",d:"Carbon"},section:"",image:"",answer:"d",solution:"",examtype:"utme",examyear:"2004"},{id:89,question:"The structural component that makes detergent dissolve more quickly in water than soap is",option:{a:"–SO3 –Na+",b:"–COO-Na+",c:"–SO4- Na+",d:"–COO-K+"},section:"",image:"",answer:"a",solution:"",examtype:"utme",examyear:"2003"},{id:142,question:"The oxidation state of chlorine in HClO4 is",option:{a:"-5",b:"-1",c:"1",d:"7"},section:"",image:"",answer:"d",solution:"",examtype:"utme",examyear:"2004"},{id:31,question:"The general formula for the alkanals is",option:{a:"ROH",b:"R2CO",c:"RCOOR1",d:"RCHO"},section:"",image:"",answer:"d",solution:"",examtype:"utme",examyear:"2001"},{id:173,question:"Which of the following alloys contain iron",option:{a:"Steel and permalloy",b:"Duralumlin and steel",c:"nd Soft Solder a Duralumlin ",d:"Brass and bronze"},section:"",image:"",answer:"a",solution:"",examtype:"utme",examyear:"2005"},{id:140,question:"Which of these compounds is a normal salt",option:{a:"NaHS",b:"NaSO4",c:"NaHCO3",d:"Na2CO3"},section:"",image:"",answer:"d",solution:"",examtype:"utme",examyear:"2004"},{id:282,question:"Iron can be protected from corrosion by coating the surface with",option:{a:"Silver",b:"Copper",c:"Zinc",d:"Gold"},section:"",image:"",answer:"c",solution:"",examtype:"utme",examyear:"2010"},{id:158,question:"Transition metals posses variable oxidation states because they have",option:{a:"Electrons in the d orbitals",b:"Electrons in the s orbitals",c:"A variable number of electrons in the p orbitals",d:"Partially filled p orbitals"},section:"",image:"",answer:"d",solution:"",examtype:"utme",examyear:"2004"},{id:3,question:"A particle that contains 9 protons, 10 neutrons and 10electrons is a",option:{a:"Neghative ion",b:"Positive ion",c:"Neutral atom of a non metal",d:"Neutral atom of a metal"},section:"",image:"",answer:"a",solution:"",examtype:"utme",examyear:"2001"},{id:220,question:"Trioxonitrate(V) acid is not used for preparing hydrogen gas from metals because it",option:{a:"Renders the metal passive",b:"Is strongly oxidizing",c:"Is volatile",d:""},section:"",image:"",answer:"a",solution:"",examtype:"utme",examyear:"2006"},{id:287,question:"2H2(g) +    O2(g)  ⇌ 2H2O(g)    ΔH   =  - ve  What happens to the equilibrium constant of the reaction above if the temperature is increased?",option:{a:"It becomes zero",b:"It decreases",c:"It increases",d:"It is unaffected"},section:"",image:"",answer:"b",solution:"",examtype:"utme",examyear:"2010"},{id:211,question:"What is the correct IUPAC name for NO2",option:{a:"Dioxonitrate(III) ion",b:"Dioxonitrate(IV) ION",c:"trioxonitrate(iii) ion",d:"trioxonitrate(iv) ion"},section:"",image:"",answer:"a",solution:"",examtype:"utme",examyear:"2005"},{id:233,question:"A difference between chemical and physical change is that in a chemical change",option:{a:"Heat is supplied",b:" A new substance is formed",c:"Oxygen is consumed",d:"A reversible process occurs"},section:"",image:"",answer:"b",solution:"",examtype:"utme",examyear:"2006"},{id:281,question:"The IUPAC nomencalatyre of the compound LiAIH4 is",option:{a:"Aluminium tetrahydrido lithium",b:"Tetrahydrido lithium aluminate (III)",c:"Lithium aluminium hydride",d:"Lithium tetrahydridoaluminate (III)"},section:"",image:"",answer:"d",solution:"",examtype:"utme",examyear:"2010"},{id:231,question:"A particle that contain s 11protons, 12 neutrons and 10 electrons is probably a",option:{a:"Metallic ion",b:"Non-metallic ion",c:"Neutral metal",d:"Neutral non-metal"},section:"",image:"",answer:"a",solution:"",examtype:"utme",examyear:"2006"},{id:161,question:"The alkyl group can be represented by the general formula",option:{a:"CnH2n+1",b:"CnH2n",c:"CnH2n+2",d:"CnH2n-2"},section:"",image:"",answer:"a",solution:"",examtype:"utme",examyear:"2004"},{id:139,question:"Calcium Tetraoxosulphate(VI) dissolves in water only sparingly to form a",option:{a:"Solution",b:"Suspension",c:"Precipitate",d:"Colloid"},section:"",image:"",answer:"d",solution:"",examtype:"utme",examyear:"2004"},{id:149,question:" N2O4(g)    ⇌  2NO2(g)",option:{a:"A constant volume",b:"An increase in pressure",c:"A decrease in pressure",d:" A decrease in volume"},section:"",image:"",answer:"c",solution:"",examtype:"utme",examyear:"2004"},{id:259,question:"The ion that will give a white precipitate with aqueous NaOH and soluble in excess of the base is",option:{a:"Zn2+",b:"Mg2+",c:"Ca2+",d:"Cu2+"},section:"",image:"",answer:"a",solution:"",examtype:"utme",examyear:"2006"},{id:21,question:"What current in amperes will deposit 2.7g of aluminium in 2 hours [Al = 27, f = 96500 C mol-1]",option:{a:"32",b:"8",c:"4",d:"16"},section:"",image:"",answer:"c",solution:"",examtype:"utme",examyear:"2001"},{id:14,question:"Environmental pollution is worsened by the release from automobile exhausts of",option:{a:"Water vapour",b:"Steam",c:"Smoke",d:"Heavy metals"},section:"",image:"",answer:"c",solution:"",examtype:"utme",examyear:"2001"},{id:192,question:"Sugar is separated from its impurities by",option:{a:"Distillation",b:"Evaporation",c:"Precipitation",d:"Crystallization"},section:"",image:"",answer:"d",solution:"",examtype:"utme",examyear:"2005"},{id:120,question:"The process by which atoms are rearranged into different molecular structures in the petroleum refining process is referred to as",option:{a:"Catalytic cracking",b:"Hydrocracking",c:"Polymerization",d:"Reforming"},section:"",image:"",answer:"d",solution:"",examtype:"utme",examyear:"2003"},{id:5,question:"An oxide X02 has a vapour density of 32. What is the atomic mass of X [O = 16]",option:{a:"32",b:"20",c:"14",d:"12"},section:"",image:"",answer:"a",solution:"",examtype:"utme",examyear:"2001"},{id:169,question:"The gas that can be dried using concentrated Tetraoxosulphate (VI) acid is",option:{a:"Ammonia",b:"Hydrogen bromide",c:"Sulphur (IV) oxide",d:"Hydrogen sulphide"},section:"",image:"",answer:"c",solution:"",examtype:"utme",examyear:"2005"},{id:278,question:"The colour of methyl orange in alkaline medium is",option:{a:"Pink",b:"Orange",c:"Red",d:"Yellow"},section:"",image:"",answer:"d",solution:"",examtype:"utme",examyear:"2010"},{id:267,question:"The stability of the noble gases is due to the fact that they",option:{a:"Have duplet or octet electron configurations",b:"Belong to group zero of the periodic table",c:"Are volatile in nature",d:"Have no electron in their outermost shells"},section:"",image:"",answer:"a",solution:"",examtype:"utme",examyear:"2010"},{id:47,question:"The formula CH2O for ethanoic acid is regarded as its",option:{a:"General formula",b:"Structural formula",c:"Molecular formula",d:"Empirical formula"},section:"",image:"",answer:"d",solution:"",examtype:"utme",examyear:"2002"},{id:13,question:"What is the decrease in volume of air when pyrogallol is shaken with 30.00cm3 of air",option:{a:"15.00cm3",b:"6.00cm3",c:"0.63cm3",d:"0.06cm3"},section:"",image:"",answer:"b",solution:"",examtype:"utme",examyear:"2001"}],n={message:e,subject:o,status:200,total:120,data:a};export{a as data,n as default,e as message,t as status,o as subject,i as total};
